Yin Kwong John Lee

1407 S. Michigan Ave., Unit 704, Chicago, IL, 60605 • (516) 589-2479 • lykjohn@umich.edu

SUMMARY

A university lecturer, data scientist, and entrepreneur with 5+ years of experience in financial investing and trading. Founder and CEO of the first financial education platform that teaches proprietary analytics to retail traders. Inspiring learners with passion and innovating education technologies with verve, I aim to democratize financial knowledge to people from all social, cultural, and demographic backgrounds.

EDUCATION

The University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI

MS Data Science, April 2021

The University of Connecticut, Storrs, CT

BA Actuarial Science and Economics, May 2019

EXPERIENCE

Aries Profits, Chicago, IL

Founder and CEO, March 2023 - Present

- Innovating course curriculums to equip learners with "elite-exlusive" data science skills that helps them develop investment/trading tools and personal wealth solutions
- Hosting a one-on-one mentorship program to help project owners build socially impactful products ranging from academic journals to industry reports, from personal blogs to podcast series, and more
- Designing marketing campaigns to drive sales and pursuing fundraises from investors

The University of Chicago, Chicago, IL

Statistics Lecturer, July 2022 - Present

- Teaching a self-designed course, Data Science in Quantitative Finance and Risk Management, to 30+ pre-college students that applies techniques like machine learning and optimization to finance
- Leading 2 teaching assistants to help improve course content and students' learning experience
- Steering students to demonstrate leadership and presentation skills through stock market games

Polygence, Stanford, CA

Research Mentor, July 2021 - Present

- Guiding 50+ high school students on financial research topics, including algorithmic trading, risk management, and portfolio analysis, leading to journal publication in a 10-week period
- Planning weekly discussion topics and goal-setting exercises to ensure publication progress

The University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI

Statistics and Data Analytics Instructor/Mentor, September 2020 - April 2021

- Instructed 150+ undergraduate Statistics students on theoretical and applied statistical topics including univariate inference, hypothesis testing, and analysis of variance using R programming
- Led new student instructors in teaching reflection and homework planning session

SKILLS

Computer: Proficient in Python, C++, R, SQL, Power BI, Tableau, VBA, Apache Spark, Hadoop, GitHub, HTML5, HTML, CSS, Wordpress, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Word, Microsoft PowerPoint

Language: Native fluency in English, Mandarin, and Cantonese